Fuxin Liu

Product Designer | UX Designer

Education

Design & TechnologyParsons School of Design

MFA, New York, USA
2018 - 2020

Interaction Design MFA, Shanghai, China Tongji University 2017 - 2018

Thermal Energy and Power Engineering

Xïan Jiaotong University
Business Administration (Minor)
Business Administration (Minor)
Business Administration (Minor)

Skill Sets

Design Methods

User Research, UI/UX Design, User Testing, Prototyping, Critiques, Wireframing, Martket Research

Design Software

Adobe Suite (Ae, Ps, Ai, Pr, Xd, Id), Cinema 4D, Figma, Sketch, Principle, Unity (Vuforia, Steam VR)

Coding

Html & Css, Javascript

Hardware

Arduino Kit, HTC Vive, Google Cardboard

Language

English, Chinese (native)

★ Honors & Awards

• China-US Youth Maker Competition

Second Prize Beijing, China. 2018.08

• **Dean Scholarship** New York, USA, 2018 - 2020

National College Student Mechanical Innovation Design Competition

Second Prize Shandong, China. 2016.08

Internet + College Student Innovation and Entrepreneurship Competition

Third Prize Shaanxi, China, 2016, 10

Profile

I have 3 years of product design experience and have worked for a startup company for one year. My job routine includes **user research**, **site map**, **framework**, **UI/UX design**, **interactive prototyping**, **and front-end development**.

I am very passionate about my job and never stop learning. I enjoy the process of solving problems, untangle complex design challenges, and optimizing user experience. With a multidisciplinary education background, I am very good at communicating and collaborating with people in different positions.

In the process of studying for my master's degree, I also got knowledge of AR/VR, motion graphics, motion capture, game design, handcrafting, physical computing, and 3D design.

Experience

Web Designer

2020.05 - Now

North America Service Center for Chinese Students LLC, New York, USA

Redesigned the company's original website with WordPress:

- Did a thorough user research through interviews and other UX methods.
- · Reorganized the information structure of the website.
- Optimized visual and interactive design.

Made the website more in line with the behavioral habits of the target consumers.

Motion Graphic Designer (Intern)

2019.12 - 2020.01

Beijing Media Network (Kaku Kids Channel), Beijing, China

Completed the video editing and post-production of multiple TV shows, and produced new media animations related to the Animation Spring Festival Gala.

User Experience Designer (Project)

2018.01 - 2018.08

Shanghai Automotive Industry Corporation, Shanghai, China

- Conducted user research and market research on electric vehicle drivers.
- Designed a self-organizing HMI system for electric vehicles based on atomic design theory.
- Designed the visual guideline for the user interface.

User Experience Designer (Project)

2017.10 - 2018.01

Philips Design, Shanghai, China

In collaboration with surgeons, programmers, and other designers in the group, designed a data visualization system of liver cancer treatment to improve the efficiency for surgeons.